Guide to the International Center for Transitional Justice (ICTJ) Records, 1981-2008
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
- Accession (2009-0193), (76 boxes)
  - ICTJ Publications (Box 14)
    - Books (Box 15)
      - Hayner, Priscilla. Unspeakable Truths: facing the challenges of truth commissions. 2002.
      - Hayner, Priscilla. Verdades innombrables: el reto de las comisiones de la verdad. 2008.
      - Henkin, Alice H., ed. The legacy of Abuse: confronting the past, facing the future. 2002.
      - Hurtado, Michael Reed, ed. Judicializacion de crimenes de sistema. 2008
      - Lutz, Ellen L. and Caitlin Reiger, eds. Prosecuting Heads of State. 2009.
      - Magarrell, Lisa and Leondardo Fillippini, eds. El legado de la verdad. 2006.
      - Romero, Mauricio. Verdad, memoria y reconstruccion. 2008
    - Miscellaneous publications
      - Administrative practices manual for internationally assisted criminal justice institutions
      - Briefing paper: Cambodian diaspora communities in transititonal jusitice. March 2008.
      - Les commissions de la verite et le ONG: le partenariat indispensable April 2004.
      - Fogotten voices: a population-based survey on attitudes about peace and justice in Northern Uganda. July 2005.
      - Hayner, Priscilla. Truth commissions: a schematic overview. June 2006
      - Justicia para las victimas: enfrentar el pasado para prevenir futuros abusos.
      - Ley de alternatividad penal y justicia transcional: documento de recomendaciones.
      - Memorialization and Democracy: state policy and civic action.
      - Memorializacion y Democracia: politicas de estado y accion civil.
      - El mosaico de la memoria: experiencias locales, no oficiales o parciales de busqueda de la verdad historica. September 2006.
      - Un pasado de violencia un futuro de paz.
      - Policy Brief: U.S. inquire into human rights abuses in the 'war on terror' by L. Magarrell, November 2008.
      - Policy Brief: Pardons by C. P. Blum, November 2008.
      - Census and identification of security system personnel after conflict: a too book for practicioners. 2007.
      - Reparative Justice series: Reparation and the Darfur peace process. November 2007.
      - Reparative Justice series: The nature and objectives of reparations.
      - International Center for Transitional Justice. (brochure)
      - ICTJ fact sheets
      - Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous Publications (Box 16)
    - Working Papers. Beyond rule of law orthodoxy the legal empowerment alternative. No. 41. October 2003.
    - Multilateral strategies to promote democracy: first report of the Empire and Democracy Project. 2003.
    - Promoting democracy through international law: second report of the Emipre and Democracy Project. 2004.
    - The impact of corporations on global governace: a report of the Empire and Democracy Project. 2004.
    - Carnegie Reporter. Vol. 3, no. 2. Spring 2005.
    - Carnegie Reporter. Vol. 2, no. 2. Spring 2003.
    - Imprint: Carnegie Council covers aftermath of the Iraq war. Summer 2004 supplement.
    - Carnegie Results. Spring 2005
    - Carnegie Results. Winter 32004.
    - Human Rights Dialogue. Series 2, no. 5. Winter 2001.
    - Combat Law: the human rights magazine. Vol. 1, no. 4. October-November 2002.
    - Combat Law: the human rights magazine. Vol. 2, no. 1. April-May 2003.
    - Combat Law: the human rights magazine. Vol. 2, no. 4. October-November 2003.
    - Combat Law: the human rights magazine. Vol. 2, no. 5. December-January 2004.
    - Combat Law: the human rights magazine. Vol. 3, no. 1. April-May Supplement 2004.
    - Combat Law: the human rights magazine. Vol. 3, no. 1. April-May 2004.
    - Combat Law: the human rights magazine. Vol. 3, no. 4. November-December 2004.
    - DCAF Backgrounder. Parlimentary oversight of intelligence services. March 2006.
    - DCAF Backgrounder. Intelligence services. March 2006.
    - DCAF Backgrounder. Contemporary challenges for the intelligence community. March 2006.
    - DCAF Policy paper No. 11. Shaping a Security Governance Agenda in Post-Conflict Peacebuilding. November 2005.
    - Development Express. Issues no. 1-7 & 9, 1997.
    - Development Express. Issues no. 1-9, 1998/1999.
    - Development Express. Issues no. 1-7, 1999-2000.
    - Development Express. Issues no. 1-3, 2000-2001.
    - Dispatches: reports from the front line - 2004
    - Steps to protection: the second Dublin platform for human rights defenders. Dublin Castle, September 10-12, 2003
    - Testimonies of human rights defenders. 2004.
    - Working Paper. Published by FRIDE, issues 17-21, 51, & 69, 2005-2008.
    - Ford Foundation Report. Summer 2001.
    - Ford Foundation Report. Winter 2002.
    - Ford Foundation Report. Winter 2003.
    - Fire and broken glass: the rise of antisemitism in Europe. published by Lawyers Committee for Human Rights, 2002.
    - A year of loss: reexamining civil liberties since September 11. published by Lawyers Committee for Human Rights, 2002.
    - New dissidents: human rights defenders and counterterrorisim in Russia. published by Human Rights First, 2005.
    - Karimov's War: human rights defenders and counterterrorism in Uzbekistan. published by Human Rights First, 2005.
    - Human Rights Brief. Vol. 12, Issue 1 (Fall 2004)
    - Human Rights Brief. Vol. 12, Issue 3 (Spring 2005)
    - Human Rights Brief. Vol. 13, Issue 1 (Fall 2005)
    - Human Rights Brief. Vol. 12, Issue 2 (Winter 2005)
    - Human Rights Brief. Vol. 15, Issue 2 (Winter 2008)
    - Empty promises: human rights protections and China's criminal procedure law in practice. Feburary 2001.
    - Implementaiton of the international convention on the elimination of all forms of racial deiscrimination in the People's Republic of China. July 2001.
    - Hidden slaves: forced labor in the United States. September 2004.
    - After the tsunami: human rights of vulnerable populations. October 2005.
    - International review of the Red Cross; humanitarian debate: law, policy, action. December 2002.
    - ICG Report. Zimbabwe at the crossroads: transition or conflict? 22 March 2002.
    - ICG Report. Courting disaster: the misrule of law in Bosnia & Herzegovina. 25 March 2002.
    - ICG Report. Colombia's elusive quest for peace. 26 March 2002.
    - International Council on Human Rights Policy Newsletter. Vol. 4, No. 3. November 2001.
    - International Council on Human Rights Policy Newsletter. Vol. 5, No. 1. March 2002.
    - International Council on Human Rights Policy Newsletter. Vol. 5, No. 2 & 3. June & November 2002.
    - International Council on Human Rights Policy Newsletter. Vol. 6, No. 1. April 2003.
    - Peaceful prevention of deadly conflict.
    - La prevencion pacifica de conflictos armados.
    - Justice Initiatives: a publication of the Open Society Justice Initiative. February 2004.
    - Justice Initiatives: a publication of the Open Society Justice Initiative. Spring 2006.
    - Voices: global rights magazine. Winter 2004.
    - Voices: global rights magazine. Summer 2005.
    - Voices: global rights magazine. Winter 2006.
    - Interights Bulletin. Vol 14, no. 1, 2002.
    - Interights Bulletin. Vol 15, no. 1, 2004.
    - UN Chronicle. Vol. 38, no. 3, September-November 2001.
    - UN Chronicle. Vol. 42, no. 2, June-August 2005.
    - Rights News. Vol. 24. no. 2, Fall 2002.
    - Rights News. Vol. 25. no. 2, Fall 2003.
    - Centerpiece: newsletter of the Weatherhead Center for International Affairs at Harvard University. Vol. 16, no. 3, Fall 2002.
    - Centerpiece: newsletter of the Weatherhead Center for International Affairs at Harvard University. Vol. 18, no. 2, Fall 2004.
    - Harvard magazine. Vol. 105, no. 3, January-February 2003.
    - Harvard magazine. Vol. 106, no. 6, July-August 2004.
    - Harvard magazine. Vol. 107, no. 3, January-February 2005.
    - Harvard magazine. Vol. 107, no. 5, May-June 2005.
    - The John F. Kennedy Library and Museum newsletter. Summer 2002
    - The John F. Kennedy Library and Museum newsletter. Winter 2002.
    - Just 'cause: Vera Institute of Justice. Vol. 12, no. 1 & 2, 2005.
    - Idebate: international debate education association. Vol. 4, issue 3, February 2004.
    - Idebate: international debate education association. Vol. 5, issue 1, September 2004.
    - Article 2. Vol 1, no. 4, August 2002.
    - International Bar News. Vol. 57, no. 1, March 2003.
    - International Bar News. Vol. 57, no. 2, June 2003.
    - Woodrow Wilson Center Update on the Americas. No. 2-6, 2002 & No. 27, 2007.
    - Quarterly Human Rights Report. Vol. 5, No. 1, January-March 2003.
    - International Peace Academy publications
      - Chesterman, Simon. East Timor in transition: from conflict prevention to state-building. May 2001.
      - Chesterman, Simon. Justice under international administration: Kosovo, East Timor and Afghanistan. September 2002. (2 copies)
      - Chesterman, Simon. Kosovo in limbo: state-building and 'substantial autonomy.' August 2001.
      - Chesterman, Simon. Tiptoeing through Afghanistan: the future of UN state-building. September 2002.
      - Chesterman, Simon. You, the people: the United Nations, transitional administration, and state-building. November 2003.
      - Chesterman, Simon, M. Ignatieff and R. Thakur. Making states work: from state failure to state-building. July 2004.
      - Groenewald, Hesta and Gordon Peake. Police reform through community-based policing… September 2004.
      - O'Neill, William G. Police reform in post-conflict societies… April 2005.
      - Samii, Cyrus. Kashmir: from persistence to progress? August 2005.
      - Tschirgi, Necla. Peacebuilding as the link between security and development… December 2003.
      - Tschirgi, Necla. Post-conflict peacebuilding revisited… 7 October 2004.
      - IPA Conference Report. Policies and practices for regulating resource flows to armed conflict. 21-23 May 2002.
      - IPA Conference Report. Strengthing the security-development nexus: assessing international policy and practice since the 1990s. April 2004.
      - IPA Meeting Note. Building partnerships for crisis prevention… April 4-5, 2006.
      - IPA Report. The Infrastructure of peace in Africa. September 2002.
      - IPA Report. The Iraq crisis and world order… December 2004.
      - IPA Report. Peacemaking in South Africa… March 2002.
      - IPA Seminar Report. The political economy of war and peace. May 6-10, 2002.
      - IPA Symposium Report. Economic agendas in armed conflict: defining and devlopping the role of the UN. March 2002.
      - IPA Workshop Report. NEPAD: African initiative, new partnership? 16 July 2002.
      - IPA Workshop Report. Creating conditions for peace: what role for the UN and regional actors? 1-3 July 2002.
      - IPA Workshop Report. Sharing best practices on conflict prevention… 8-10 April 2002.
      - Post-conflict transitions: national experience and international reform. Meeting summary. March 28-29, 2005
      - The UN Security Council's counterterrorism program: what lies ahead? 2007.
    - Regards croises. 2003. (Box 18)
    - Manuel for conflict analysis. 2006.
    - Linking migration, HIV/AIDS and urban food security in Southern and Eastern Africa. 2007.
    - Sintesis del informe final de la IER
    - Synthese du rapport final.
    - Summary of the final report. (in 4 languages)
    - The Khmer Rouge and national reconciliation - opinions from the Cambodians. April 2002.
    - Protecting two million internally displaced: the successes and shortcomings of the African Union in Darfur. November 2005.
    - Political killings in Kosova/Kosovo. March-June 1999.
    - When displacement ends: a framework for durable solutions. 2007.
    - A time for change: rethinking US-Cuba policy. May 2002.
    - Human security brief 2006
    - Love, loss, and longing: the impact of U.S. travel policy on Cuban-American families. 2007.
    - Insider mediators. 2009.
    - Democracy Backgrounder. March 2006
    - Republic of Kenya. Report of the task force on the establishment of a Truth Justice and Reconciliation Commission," 26 August 2003
    - A call for justice: a national consultaion on past human rights violations in Afghanistan.
    - All-Africa conference on African priciples of conflic resolution and reconciliation. November 8-12, 1999.
    - La violencia homicida y otros patrones de grave afectacion a los derechos humanos en El Salvador 2006.
    - Dy, Khamboly. A history of Democratic Kampuchea (1975-1979). 2007.
    - ReVista: Harvard review of Latin America. Vol. VII, no. 2 (Winter 2008)
    - ReVista: Harvard review of Latin America. Vol. VIII, no. 3 (Spring 2009)
    - Berghof Handbook Dialogue Series. A systemic approach to conflict transformation. 2008.
    - Berghof Handbook Dialogue Series. Peacebuilding at a Crossroads? 2009.
    - Managing complexity: political and managerial challenges in United Nations Peace Operations. July 2009.
    - CMI Research for Development and Justice 2008
    - The Centre on Human Rights in Conflict, policy paper no. 2, May 2009.
    - The Centre on Human Rights in Conflict, policy paper no. 3, June 2009.
    - Materials for working visit of the judges of the special court for Sierra Leone to the International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia. 25-28 June 2004. Vol. 1
    - Materials for working visit of the judges of the special court for Sierra Leone to the International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia. 25-28 June 2004. Vol. 2
    - Department of Peacekeeping Operations Human Trafficking Resource Package.
    - Teaching guide to regret to inform.
    - The report of the Constitution of Kenya Review Commission. Short version. 2002.
    - Advances in understanding international peacemaking. Volume II, 1996-2000.
    - East Timor Human Development Report 2002.
    - Bloomfield, David. On good terms: clarifying reconciliation. October 2006
    - Dudouet, Veronique. From war to politices: resistance/liberation movements in transition. April 2009.
    - Enns, Diane. Identity and victimhood: questions for conflict management practice. May 2007.
    - Fischer, Martina. Civil society in conflict transformation: abivalence, potentials and challeges. October 2006. (2 copies)
    - Baldwin, Clive, Chris Chapman and Zie Gray. Minority rights: the key to conflict prevention. 2007
    - Taneja, Preti. Assimilation, exodus, eradication: Iraq's minority communities since 2003. 2007.
    - Mali Kalendar velikhi zlocina. 1996.
    - Memorandum of understanding between the government of the Republic of Indonesia and the Free Aceh Movement.
    - The essence of reparations. 2003
    - The position of the Citizens' Forum for Constitutional Reform on the review of the 1999 Constitution of the Federal Republic of Nigeria.
    - Constitution of the Republic of Uganda. 1995.
    - English translation of Special Prosecutor's report from the Special Prosecutor's office in Ethiopia.
    - Truth and Reconciliation in Sierra Leone. December 2001.
    - Redress. Implementando los derecho de las victimas. March 2006.
    - Redress. Erradicando la tortura. March 2006.
    - Redress. Zimbabwe: tortuous patterns destined to repeat themselves in upcoming election campaign. November 2004
    - Preparar el futuro: conflicto y post-conflicto en Colombia. 2002.
    - Masacres en Guatemala. 2000.
    - Wein na di speshal kot? The Special Court made simple. 2003.
    - Religion and politics in Ghana. 1992.
    - D'ombre et de lumiere: bilbiographi des violations graves des droits de l'homme au Maroc. 2004.
    - Phepha! Be safe.
    - Hallazgo de fosas conrestos humano en el districto de Vinchos. 2004.
    - Community-based development-oriented peace and rights-based education for the Bangsamoro.
    - Conflicto y paz en Colombia. 2004.
    - By all means: the Russian Federation Ministry of Internal Affairs operation in the village of Samashki; April 7-8, 1995.
    - La mediacion como herramienta para la resolucion de conflictos armados internos. 2003.
    - Iraq: the day after. 2003.
    - Behind their backs: Russian forces' use of civilians as hostages and human shields duringthe Chechnya war. 1997.
    - When the powers fall: reconcilation in the healing of nations. 1998.
    - Together against torture. 2001.
    - Mujeres privadas de libertad.
    - La paz y sus principios. 2002.
    - Gendering humanitarianism. 2000.
    - Truth and reconciliation in times of conflict: the South African model. July 29, 2002.
    - La femme dans la tournemente des guerres en R.D. Congo. 2003.
    - Women's rights violations during the conflict in the Democratic Republic of the Congo. 2002
    - Constitution of the Federal Republic of Nigeria, 1999 (simplified & abridged.
    - Cochas Paca y Oreja de Perro.
    - Sierra Leone's Truth & Reconciliation Commission and Special Court: a citizen's handbook.
    - An annotated bibliography on women in conflict. 1999.
    - Legal and judicial sector assessment manuel. July 2002.
    - Initiatives in legal and judicial reform. 2004.
    - Journal of Consitutional Affairs. No. 21, April 2005.
    - I promise I would tell. 1993.
    - Para no olvidarlas mas: mujeres y reparaciones en el Peru. 2007.
    - Human rights in Mexico: a policy of impunity. June 1990.
    - Truth and partial justice in Argentina. April 1991.
    - Human rights based programming: how to do it.
    - Harvard Human Rights Journal. Vol. 19 (Spring 2006).
    - Genocide and accountability. 2004.
    - The murder of Dele Giwa. 2001.
    - Rompiendo el silencio. 2008.
    - Hilando Suenos y sentimientos. 2000.
    - Desarrollo en el refugio esperanza y desafios de la cooperation con el Sahara.
  - CPU Materials (Box 19)
    - Guatemala (Law)
    - Peru
    - Morocco/Middle East
    - Bosnia/Herzegovina
    - East Timor (Academics)
    - East Timor (Law/legislation)
    - East Timor (Programs/projects)
    - East Timor (Official works)
    - East Timor
    - North Ireland (Articles/reports)
    - South Africa
    - Zimbabwe
    - Miscellaneous
    - Retroactivity (Box 20)
    - Truth commissions
    - Prosecutions (Domestic/international)
    - Report on UN Peace operations
    - Restorative justice
    - Transitional Constitutions in comparative perspective
    - International law
    - Transitional justice
    - ICC
    - Afghanistan (General information)
    - Afghanistan
    - Afghanistan (Law/legislation)
    - Argentina
    - Chile
    - El Salvador
    - Guatemala (Articles/reports)
  - Miscellaneous Publications (Box 21)
    - Draft report on globalization. by George Soros. 2001.
    - Sida. March 2003.
    - Sida. June 2003.
    - Sida. September 2003.
    - Brochure: A United Nations Emergency Peace Service.
    - Human Rights Center Annual Report 2007.
    - Kenya Human Rights Commission Annual Report 2001-2002.
    - Kenya Human Rights Commission Annual Report 2002-2003.
    - Searching for the truth: magazine of the Documentation Center of Cambodia. July 2003
    - Searching for the truth: magazine of the Documentation Center of Cambodia. 4 quarterly issues from 2004.
    - New York Nonprofits. Vol 24, no. 6, 8 & 9, 2007.
    - Linking Solidarity Newsletter. October 2003.
    - Linking Solidarity Newsletter. 2005.
    - DPF Annual Report 2006.
    - 44th Street Notes. Vol. 19, no. 3 (March), 5 (May) & 7 (Sept.) 2004.
    - Abducted: the Lord's Resistence Army and forced conscription in northern Uganda. June 2007.
    - New World. October-December 2006.
    - Helping prevent violent conflict
    - ILAC Report. Liberia, December 2003.
    - ILAC Report. Haiti, January 2005.
    - ILAC Annual Report 2005.
    - Workshop at Rutgers. To prevent genocide and crimes agains humanity. March 29, 2007.
    - The Tinker Foundation, Inc. 2006.
    - ESCR-Net. Information booklet.
    - Crosscurrent: newsletter of the Washington Office on Latin America. Feb. & July 2005 issues.
    - WOLA Briefing Series, October 2002 & December 2004.
    - WOLA Conference Report. August 2005.
    - WOLA Special Report. November 2004 & July & October 2005.
    - Erasing the Lines. December 2005
    - Peacewatch. Vol. VIII, no. 6/Vol. IX, no. 1, October/December 2002.
    - Peacewatch. Vol. IX, no. 2, February 2003.
    - Peacewatch. Vol. X, no. 2, June 2004 & no. 4 December 2004/January 2005.
    - Peacewatch. Vol. XI, no. 2, August/September 2005.
    - Open Society News. Summer 2001.
    - Open Society News. Winter 2002.
    - Open Society News. Fall-Winter 2002/3.
    - Open Society News. Spring-Summer 2004.
    - The Reparation Report. Issue 3, April 2004.
    - The Transatlantic Quarterly. Vol. 1, no. 2, Summer 2004.
    - The Transatlantic Quarterly. Vol. 1, no. 3, Winter/Spring 2005.
    - United States Institutes of Peace publications
      - Special Report. February 15, 2001.
      - Special Report. October 22, 2001.
      - Special Report. November 14, 2001.
      - Special Report. December 17, 2001.
      - Special Report. April 22, 2002.
      - Special Report. May 1 & 15, 2002.
      - Special Report. No. 91 & 92, July & August 2002.
      - Special Report. No. 95-97, November-December 2002.
      - Special Report. No. 100, February 2003.
      - Special Report. No. 109, August 2003.
      - Special Report. 2004 issues, No, 118 (April) 123 (July), & 128 (November)
      - Special Report. 2005 issues, No. 130 (Feb), 134-136, 139 (Apr-May), 142 & 144 (July), 145 (Aug), 147 (Sept), 152 (Oct) & 155 (Nov)
      - El Salvador implementaiton of the peace accords. January 2001.
      - Training for peace and humanitarian relief operations: advancing best practices. April 2002.
      - The ethics of armed humanitarian intervention. July 2002.
      - The Palestinian reform agenda. December 2002.
      - Downward spiral: HIC/AIDS, state capacity, and political conflict in Zimbabwe. July 2004.
    - Violence and Transition
      - As for violent crime that's our daily bread: vigilante violence during South Africa's period of transition.
      - From low intensity war to mafia war: taxi violence in South Africa (1987-2000)
      - Guardian or gangster?
      - Guns, pagad and the state: vigilantism and revenge violenc in the Western Cape.
      - A foreign experience: violence, crime and xenophobia during South Africa's transition.
    - Democratic Transition in Post-Conflict Societies Project
      - International assistance for institution building in post-conflic Cambodia.
      - Democracy assistence to post-conflict Ethiopia.
      - The limits of 'no-party' politics.
      - Democracy assistence to post-conflict Guatemala.
      - Supporting the post-genocide transition in Rwanda.
      - Go beyond first aid…post-conflic Sierra Leone.
  - Institutional Materials (Box 22)
    - Indonesia
    - Literature Survey on Hybrid Tribunals
    - Afghanistan
    - Cambodia: National Legal System
    - Nigeria
    - Summary of Personal Interviews of ICTJ Staff and Associates, February 2, 2004 (spiral bound)
    - A Workshop for the International Center for Transitional Justice, February 4, 2004 (spiral boud)
    - A Review of ICTJ Learning Event Materials, January 16, 2004 (spiral bound)
    - Professor Bickford: Human Rights, Democracy & Traditional Justice (bound)
    - Professor Van Zyl. Part 2, Fall 2005 Course Packet (bound)
    - 3-ring binder, Supporting materials for ICTJ's GTRC Workshop, September 27-28, 2004
    - First Hand-out Organigrams
    - ICTJ paper on TRC in Sierra Leone, 24 June 2004
    - Materials on Liberia
    - Conference Report: Vancouver Dialogue on the Impunity Gap. April 4, 2004
    - ICTJ publications
    - ICTJ Annual Reports
    - Demi Kebenaran: pemetaan upaya-upaya pencarian keadilan dalam masa transisi di Indonesia published by ICTJ (bound)
    - ICTJ publication, The Struggle for Truth and Justice: a survey of Transitional Justice Initiatives throughout Indonesia (bound)